datanami.com 2014-04-05

# Datanami: Our privacy policy at Datanami and Tabor Communications, Inc. - Datanami

At Tabor Communications Incorporated ("TCI"), we value and protect your privacy. We thank you for the trust that you place in us and we want you to know that the information you share with us will be treated with care. 

The objective of our Privacy Statement is to disclose and explain what information we collect, use, and share and to explain the privacy choices that you can make. We encourage you to read our Privacy Statement as well as those of all websites that you visit. 

This Privacy Statement applies to any information collected by TCI or its vendors via: (1) the websites owned or operated by TCI ("TCI Websites" or "Websites"), (2) e-mail or any electronic newsletters in which you enroll, (3) offline means such as telephone, traditional mail, or in person, or (4) any other online or offline means in connection with TCI generally or with any of the TCI products and services. TCI may provide links to third-party websites. Since we do not control third-party sites and are not responsible for any information you may provide while on such sites, we encourage you to read the privacy policies on those sites before providing any of your personally identifiable information ("PII") on such sites. 

Effective Date: January 1, 2008 

### WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND  
HOW WE USE IT 

  * The Information We Collect
  * How We Use and Share The Information We Collect
  * Using Your E-mail Address
  * Advertisements That Link to Our Websites
  * Transfers of Information to Other Countries

### The Information We Collect 

When you visit the TCI Websites, we or our vendors collect information, including PII that you provide, in order to provide you with the products and services you requested or with offers or promotions that may interest you, service your accounts, and save you time and better respond to your needs. 

We use cookie technology to collect website statistical information and to improve your customer experience with the TCI websites. Cookies set by TCI do not capture any PII. However, if you choose to furnish us with PII, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie to further enhance your experience with our websites. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at our websites (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our websites), save your password in password-protected areas, and enable you to use shopping carts on our websites. We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs, or services. 

When browsing the TCI websites, you may choose not to provide us with any PII, such as by choosing not to register or to login. When you browse in this way, we will not link your cookie information with the account(s) you may have with TCI. 

We or our vendors also automatically collect some statistical data as you browse our websites. For example, we automatically collect your IP Address used to connect your computer to the Internet, browser type and version, operating system and platform, average time spent on our websites, pages viewed, information searched for, access times, Clickstream Data, and other relevant information about your online experience. 

TCI may also use web beacons to present offers on the TCI Websites, or other websites on which TCI advertises. In addition, e-mail offers that we send you may contain Web Beacons to help us record response rates, assist in measuring the offer's effectiveness, and/or generally enhance the relevance of e-mail offers. We sometimes use vendors to manage web beacons and the data they collect; however, web beacons do not capture any PII that you enter on the TCI Websites. 

We or our vendor also collect information, including PII, that you provide via telephone, traditional mail, e-mail, in person, or otherwise. 

At some TCI Websites and through certain promotions, you can submit information, including PII, about other people. For example, if you order a gift online or offline and want it sent directly to the recipient, we might collect the recipient's name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number. 

### How We Use and Share The Information We Collect 

TCI uses the information we or our vendors collect about you and others, including PII, to complete transactions, respond to your requests, deliver the products and services in which you enroll or request, and notify you of updates, products, services, offers, or promotions that may interest you. We may process or combine your information with other information that is publicly available. This enables us to customize your customer experience and provide you with more relevant offers. TCI may also use the information that we or our vendors collect from you online and via other means to market to you through alternative channels. 

TCI may share your information within our Tabor Communication, Inc family of companies. To provide products and services to you or offers that may interest you, we may also share your information with carefully selected vendors with whom we work. This includes companies that manage accounts and companies that perform marketing services and other business operations for us. All companies that act on our behalf are required to safeguard PII. 

TCI may share your information with business partners carefully selected by us that may wish to offer you products or services that may interest you, either in conjunction with TCI or by themselves. 

We may also use or disclose your information, including PII, to comply with the law or in response to a subpoena, court order, government request, or other legal process, or as otherwise permitted by law; to report or collect debts owed; to reduce fraud or criminal activity; to protect the legal rights of TCI, our customers, our Websites, or the users of our Websites; or to allow a purchaser of a TCI division, or TCI as a whole, to continue using your information to serve you or as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Statement. 

Regarding Tabor Research studies: Data collected for market research or other studies will be used only in aggregate; no data linking respondents to specific study answers will be released. Respondent PII will not be released without specific prior permission. Respondents also have the option of identifying their organization either by name, or organization type (e.g. Large Product Manufacturer). PII information will be used to send respondants rewards, and/or study summary results as appropriate. 

### Using Your E-Mail Address 

We may use your e-mail address for the following types of e-mail messages: 

  * Account Service Communications. We may send you communications related to TCI products and services in which you are enrolled (e.g., subscription and membership communications). 
  * Updates and Valuable Offers. We may send you e-mail account updates, offers for our products and services, requests for enrollment, as well as valuable offers from our business partners that we send you on their behalf. 
  * Regularly Scheduled E-mail Newsletters that you elected to receive. 

You can also elect to receive other types of e-mail messages from us, including alerts and notifications. 

### Advertisements That Link to Our Websites 

TCI hires vendors to place advertisements on the TCI Websites and our banner advertisements on other websites, and to perform tracking and reporting activities on the TCI Websites and other websites. This enables us to learn which advertisements and websites bring users to our Websites and to improve the user experience. Cookies are used to assist with these activities. In doing so, a unique cookie is placed on your computer either by us or a vendor in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Statement. 

This Privacy Statement does not cover any use of information that such vendors may have collected from you or the methods used by them to collect that information. Rather, such vendors have their own privacy policies. If you would like more information about their privacy policies, including information on how to opt out of their tracking methods, please contact those sites directly. 

### Transfers of Information to Other Countries 

Some of the uses and disclosures mentioned in this Privacy Statement may involve the transfer of your PII to various countries around the world. By submitting your PII to TCI via a TCI Website or otherwise, you consent to such transfers. 

### YOUR COMMUNICATION AND PRIVACY CHOICES 

  * How To Opt Out of Receiving Offers and Promotions 

TCI respects the choices that you make regarding your privacy. You may request that we no longer send you e-mails and/or offline offers or promotions, or share your information with our business partners that are interested in providing you with offers and promotions that may interest you. 

### Privacy Choices: How to Opt Out of Receiving Offers and Promotions 

  * If you do not want to receive future offers or promotions from TCI via e-mail, please contact us. In addition, if you have elected to receive certain marketing e-mails from TCI but decide that you no longer want to receive them, you may also follow the unsubscribe instructions that are located at the bottom of those e-mail messages. 
  * If you do not want to receive future offers or promotions from TCI via offline means, please contact us at the address listed below. 
  * If you do not want us to share your e-mail address with our business partners in the future so that they can e-mail you information about products or services that may interest you, please let us know. 
  * If you do not want us to share your PII with our business partners in the future so that they can use offline means to provide you with information about products or services that may interest you, please contact us. 

Please note that even if you opt out of receiving e-mails and/or offline offers or promotions, we may continue to send you service notifications via e-mails or offline means that are related to your account(s) and other products and services you have requested or in which you are currently enrolled. These include e-mails that provide account information (including information about the expiration and possible renewal of any subscription you have with TCI and other servicing communications based on your customer status), answer your questions about a product or service, facilitate or confirm a sale, or fulfill a legal or regulatory requirement. 

### SECURING YOUR INFORMATION 

We use reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security measures to protect your PII from unauthorized access and use. Do not use e-mail to send us any PII, since it would be unencrypted and can be read by anyone who receives or intercepts it. 

### UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION 

If you wish to correct or update the PII related to your TCI account(s), please contact us at the address listed below. 

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT 

TCI reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting revisions on this Website. Such changes will be effective upon posting. 

### CONTACTING TCI 

Contact TCI (address listed below) if you have any questions about this Privacy Statement. 

### GLOSSARY OF KEY TERMS 

Business Partner \- A Business Partner is any third party with which TCI conducts business, except that the term Business Partner does not include a Vendor, as defined below. 

Clickstream Data \- Clickstream Data is information that users generate as they move from page to page and click on items within a website, usually stored in log files. Website designers can use Clickstream Data to improve users' experiences with a website. 

Cookie \- A Cookie is a small piece of information that a website transfers to the hard drive of a visitor's computer for record-keeping purposes. Cookies provide visitors a personalized experience on the Websites owned or operated by TCI by enabling us to determine unique preferences and trends based on visits to these Websites and to other websites. 

IP Address \- An IP Address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically and required for using the Internet. 

Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") \- PII is information collected online or offline by TCI or by our Vendors that identifies the person to whom such information pertains, including without limitation name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address. 

Vendor \- A Vendor is any third party that performs business operations on behalf of TCI, including without limitation printing, mailing services and other communications services (e.g., e-mail, direct mail, or otherwise), marketing, data processing, customer acquisition and servicing, collections, or advertisement management. 

Web Beacon \- A Web Beacon, also known as a "clear GIF" (a common format for image files), is an invisible file located on web pages that you visit. They are often used in combination with a Cookie to track navigation of a site. If you visit a page on a website owned or operated by TCI that contains a Web Beacon, it communicates with your computer to determine, among other things, whether you have been to that page before or viewed a particular advertisement. 

### OPTING OUT OF TCI E-MAIL OFFERS AND PROMOTIONS 

If you are a customer of a TCI product or service and do not want to receive future offers or promotions from TCI via offline means (such as traditional mail and telephone), please contact customer service at: 

Tabor Communications, Inc.  
8445 Camino Santa Fe  
Suite 101  
San Diego, CA 92121  
Phone: (858) 625-0070  
Fax: (858) 625-0088  
General Email: [remove@hpcwire.com](mailto:remove@hpcwire.com)
